The elderly residents in care homes in London are being given hens to look after to stop them feeling lonely.
伦敦养老院的老年住户正陆续领到母鸡来照料，以免他们感到孤独。
The project was dreamed up by a local charity to reduce loneliness and improve elderly people’s wellbeing.
这个项目是当地一家慈善组织构想出来的，旨在减少老年人的孤独感，增进他们的身心健康。
It is also being used to help patients suffering from dementia, a serious illness of the mind.
该项目还用于帮助痴呆症患者——痴呆症是一种严重的心智疾病。
Staff in care homes have reported a reduction in the use of medicine where hens are in use.
养老院的工作人员反映，在用上了母鸡的地方，用药有所减少。
Among those taking part in the project is 80-year-old Ruth Xavier.
参与这个项目的人当中，就有80岁的露丝·泽维尔。
She said: “I used to keep hens when I was younger and had to prepare their breakfast each morning before I went to school.”
她说：“我年轻时养过母鸡，每天早上上学前都得给它们准备早饭。”
“I like the project a lot.
“我非常喜欢这个项目。
I am down there in my wheelchair in the morning letting the hens out and down there again at night to see they’ve gone to bed.”
早上我坐着轮椅下去把母鸡放出来，晚上再下去看看它们是不是已经回窝睡觉了。”
“It’s good to have a different focus.
“有点别的事情可以上心，挺好的。
People have been bringing their children in to see the hens and residents come and sit outside to watch them.
一直有人带着孩子进来看母鸡，住户们也会到外面坐着看它们。
I’m enjoying the creative activities, and it feels great to have done something useful.”
我很喜欢这些创意活动，做了点有用的事，感觉真好。”
There are now 700 elderly people looking after hens in 20 care homes in the North East, and the charity has been given financial support to roll it out countrywide.
目前，英格兰东北部地区的20家养老院里有700位老人在照料母鸡，这家慈善组织也已获得资金支持，要把这一项目推广到全国。
Wendy Wilson, extra care manager at 60 Penfold Street, one of the first to embark on the project, said: “Residents really welcome the idea of the project and the creative sessions.
彭福尔德街60号是最早开展这一项目的养老院之一，那里的特别护理经理温迪·威尔逊说：“住户们非常欢迎这个项目的理念和那些创意活动课。
We are looking forward to the benefits and fun the project can bring to people here.”
我们期待这个项目能给这里的人们带来益处和乐趣。”
Lynn Lewis, director of Notting Hill Pathways, said: “We are happy to be taking part in the project.
诺丁山路径组织（Notting Hill Pathways）的负责人林恩·刘易斯说：“我们很高兴能参与这个项目。
It will really help connect our residents through a shared interest and creative activities.”
它会借助共同的兴趣和创意活动，切实帮助我们的住户彼此建立联系。”